好了  姑娘小伙们
Ok, boys and girls.
猜猜古怪班尼现在要做什么动物了
Guess what kind of animal Wacky Benny is making now?
它有一个大头
It gets a big head.
是死掉的动物吧
Is it a dead animal?
我想还是别让他再出丑了
I say we put him out of his misery
把艾玛的蛋糕拿出来吧
and bring out Emma's cake.
他也是刚入行不久
He's so new to this.
如果把他轰下台  他怎么能从中受益呢
How's he gonna learn if we stop his act?
你真是个笨小丑
You're a sucky clown.
你真是个臭屁的观众
And you're a super-duper audience.
这样做可不行了
Hey, that is not okay.
别碰我儿子
Hey, keep your hands off my son.
你告诉他先别碰我
Tell him to keep his hand off me.
我的四肢动不了了
I can't move my arm or leg.
总监：
zlean
一名完全健康的青少年怎么会突然轻微中风呢
So how does a completely healthy teenager have a mini-stroke?
脑部CT扫描和脑血管造影的结果均正常
Head CT and cerebral angiogram are normal.
凝血参数也正常
Clotting parameters are normal.
你们没看见他衬衣上有一处褶皱
You're forgetting the wrinkly clump in the middle of his shirt.
我以为咱们是要先诊断这个中年小丑呢
Thought we'd diagnose the middle-aged clown first.
估计是安全带勒的
It's probably from my seat belt.
褶皱的纹理毫无规律
Wrinkle pattern's too varied.
看上去像是被什么人推了或是抓了一下
It looks like someone shoved you or grabbed you.
或者是纸尿裤袋子弄的
Probably from the diaper bag.
如果病人有毒瘾
If the patient's using drugs,
可卡因可能引起他大脑中的动脉痉挛
cocaine could have caused an arterial spasm in his brain.
毒性检测显示他没有吸毒
The tox screen was clean.
我猜是被你劈腿的前女友抓的
I'm gonna say it was the ex-girlfriend you cheated on,
而不是陪你劈腿的前妻
not the ex-wife you cheated with.
如果后者要对你动手
If the latter was prone to violence,
你早就被打得满地找牙了
you'd have been scattered in various dumpsters years ago.
有没有搞错
Seriously?
除了我没人想聊聊病人的情况吗
No one else wants to talk about the patient?
崭新的办公室家具  还是肉色主题
New office furniture. Meaty topic.
前妻的赔率是多少
What's the action on the ex-wife?
是瑞秋的男友菲尔干的
It was Rachel's boyfriend Phil.
他的公司把他调回波特兰了
His company's moving him back to Portland.
他想让我调整我照看孩子的时间
He wants me to change my visitation order
好让瑞秋和我女儿
so he can ask Rachel and my daughter to
搬到西边和他一起住
move out west with him.
我们越吵越厉害
Things got a little heated.
病人被打中要害
The patient was punched in the groin.
会不会引起大量交感神经释放冲动
Could have triggered a massive sympathetic discharge.
颈动脉超声正常
Carotid duplex is normal.
谁更合适当这个父亲呢
Who's better qualified to be the Daddy?
是那个只提供了一半DNA的家伙
The guy who spilled a little DNA in her gene pool
还是日夜守护在她身边
or the guy who's gonna be there day and night
向她教授类似不要在离婚后
to pass on important values
把妈妈肚子搞大这类人生道理的家伙呢
like not shtupping Mommy after the divorce?
我才是她的父亲
I am her Daddy.
她必须留在这
She's staying here.
豪斯说得有道理
House has a point.
每周轮着陪孩子  能让你感觉好受些
A couple nights a week with each kid may make you feel better.
但取代不了时时刻刻陪伴在旁的父母啊
Doesn't replace two 'round-the-clock parents.
不管是不是时刻在一起
'Round-the-clock or not,
为人父母都是项无法完成的工作
parenting's an impossible job.
反正都会搞砸的
No way not to mess it up.
陶博干嘛不去趟这浑水呢
Why shouldn't Taub be the one to do it?
-谢谢你  -有道理
- Thank you. - Makes sense.
朴克的虎妈狼爸着实让人难以忍受
Park's tiger Mom and Dad were so insufferable.
她得用小时计算父母的爱
She has to measure their affection in hours.
奇斯那只顾事业的父亲和酗酒的母亲也一样
Chase's careerist dad and alcoholic mom were so indifferent.
只会让他相信父母都靠不住
He has to believe it's a wash.
到你了
Your turn.
你不负责任的双亲是怎么
What did your screwed-up parents do
扭曲你对为人父母的看法的
to screw up your view of parenting?
他们是负责任的好父母
They were good parents.
这是矛盾的
That's an oxymoron.
奇斯说的对
Chase is right.
所有父母都会毁了自己的孩子
All parents screw up all children.
他现在还在走神  但这就没关系了
He's also dreamy, but it's not relevant now.
这么说所有父母都在毁掉自己的孩子
So all parents screw up all children,
但在我自己抚养女儿和让她离开之间
but it makes some huge difference
就有天壤之别了吗
if I keep my daughter here or let her move?
心内膜炎
Endocarditis.
他大脑中有一片赘生物
Flipped a piece of vegetation into his brain,
有可能在血管造影前就破碎了
which could have broken up before the angiogram.
用经食道心脏超声来确认一下
Transesophageal echo to confirm.
你最好还是放她走
Screwed up is your best case.
夹在风情万种的工作狂父亲
Bouncing between a philandering workaholic Dad
和被劈腿后十分痛苦的母亲中间
and an embittered, sexually betrayed Mom,
她会让你俩成为糟糕父母的领军人物
it's gonna lead to screwed-up squared.
心内膜炎可以治愈吗
Is endocarditis treatable?
没问题
Very.
用超声能看出他心脏瓣膜上是否长有异物
The echo will show us any growths on his heart valve.
一般情况下吃吃药就可以了
Most likely meds will be enough.
都不用动手术
He won't even need surgery.
他的表演事业才刚起步
He's just taken up performing
他现在压力挺大的
and it's very stressful for him.
会不会是这个原因
Could that have caused this?
没什么压力  我很开心
It's not stressful. I have fun.
压力可能没什么关系
Stress wouldn't be relevant,
但能引起他肾上腺素升高的因素
but anything that increases his adrenalin
倒是会让他的情况更糟
could have made it worse.
也许我们能给你找一个新爱好
Maybe we find you a new hobby,
你更擅长的爱好
one you're a little better at.
我会越演越好的  而且那不只是个爱好
I'm gonna get better at it, and it's not a hobby.
我想到马戏团去当职业小丑
I-I think I want to get a job working as a circus clown,
为别人带来欢乐
making people laugh.
本  我想这可不是个好主意
Ben, I-I don't think that's a good idea.
我爸就会认为这挺好的
It was good enough for my Dad.
你是...
You're a, uh--
不是他  他是指他的生父
No, his biological father.
他的病会不会跟他生父的黑色素瘤有关呢
Could his Dad's melanoma be a factor here?
应该也没关系
That wouldn't be related.
本  你根本不了解他
Ben, you barely knew him.
你是个很聪明的孩子
You're such a smart kid.
你的志向可以更远大一些
You could aim a lot higher
而不是在脸上涂油彩  扔水瓶子
than face paint and seltzer bottles.
我需要治疗我的二型糖尿病
I need treatment for my type 2 diabetes.
你刚才那句话没有一点是真的
There is absolutely no part of that sentence that is true.
我的体重在增加  时常感到疲劳
I've been experiencing weight gain, fatigue,
还爱发呆
and sluggishness.
体重下降才是糖尿病的症状
Weight loss is a symptom of diabetes.
疲劳是因为
Fatigue is a symptom
你总以为自己得了你没有得的病
of thinking you have a disease you don't actually have,
而发呆是由疲劳引起的
and sluggishness is a synonym of fatigue.
我需要注射胰岛素  我知道的
I need insulin. I know it.
虽然我特别想把你血糖
Much as I'd like to kill you
降到危险值  杀了你
by dangerously lowering your blood sugar,
但谋杀会让我失去假释
murder violates my parole.
这血检结果是一周前的
That bloodwork is week's old.
再给我检测一下
Test me again.
我就是血检  结果就是你没有糖尿病
I am the test. The test is negative.
结果还说你是个讨厌鬼
The test also thinks you're a giant pain in the ass.
最后这句骂你的话是告诉你该离开了
That last insult was your cue to leave.
给我做血检
Test me.
好吧  在这等着
Fine. Wait right here.
谢谢你
Thank you.
睡眠研究
Sleep study.
请保证他在接下来的八个小时内不受打扰
Please make sure he's not disturbed for the next eight hours.
我们得谈谈周六晚上的事
We need to talk about Saturday night.
不行  不行  不行
No, no, no, no, no.
历史学家才要谈周六晚上的事呢  不是我们
Historians will talk of Saturday night, not us.
在那个传奇之夜
The legendary night on
我们将看桑托斯打碎卢比奥的下巴
which we watch Santos shatter Rubio's jaw
你还会输给我意义重大的五十块
and you epically pay me $50.
我有个机会能去现场看
I have a chance to really watch it.
我的一位病人有两张票  他自己用不成
A patient of mine has a pair of tickets he can't use,
而你只能待在家里或是办公室里
and obviously you're under house and office arrest.
我只是想确认下你不会介意
I just wanted to make sure you were cool
我独自去大西洋城
if I go to Atlantic city without you.
不介意  谢啦
Uh, no, thanks.
恐怕我得拒绝
I'm afraid I'm gonna have to decline
你要我别和你共度周六夜晚的邀请了
your invitation to not spend Saturday night with you.
座位可就在拳击台底下
These are ringside seats.
摄像机也在拳击台底下
Cameras are ringside too.
如果你愿意  我也可以把汗  口水还有血
If you want, I could sweat and spit
时不时的往你身上洒
and bleed on you from time to time.
如果可以  我一定带你去
I'd take you if I could.
只要咱俩中有人能去  我就会去
Well, I'd take me if either of us could.
我还真是处于两难的境地啊
See what a tough spot I'm in?
我要去看那场比赛
I'm going to that fight.
好吧  另一张票给我
All right, I'll take the other ticket.
让我来操心怎么去的问题
Let me worry about logistics.
病人的心脏瓣膜正常
Patient's heart valves are normal.
不是心内膜炎
It's not endocarditis.
但他心包膜增厚  说不通啊
But he has a thickened pericardium, which makes no sense.
他心脏有问题
He has a heart problem
但却不是导致短暂性脑缺血发作的原因
but not one that could have caused his T.I.A.
梅毒性血管炎可能导致短暂性脑缺血发作
Syphilitic vasculitis would explain the T.I.A.
和心包膜炎
and the pericardial inflammation.
梅毒测试呈阴性
Syph test was negative.
此外  这个孩子从来没有过性行为
Plus, the kid's never been sexually active.
这个  我从他的病例
Yeah, I got that from the line in his chart
"生日小丑"那一栏就知道了
that says "Birthday clown."
他的生父是马戏团小丑
His late father was a circus clown.
组织胞浆菌病
Histoplasmosis?
他没有免疫系统缺陷
He's not immuno-compromised.
我想你将这无关紧要的一点提出来
And I assume you added that irrelevant tidbit
是因为他对父亲盲目的敬意打动了你
because you're moved by the son's idiotic tribute
觉得你也理应把女儿留在新泽西
and think it justifies keeping your daughter in New Jersey.
如果他免疫系统过于活跃呢
What if he has a heightened immune system?
我提到这一点是因为
I mentioned it because...
慢慢来  不着急
Take your time.
我们先继续讨论医学
We'll continue with the medicine.
干燥综合症可能导致慢性心包炎
Sjogren's could have given him chronic pericarditis
及脑动脉炎
and cerebral arteritis.
就是干燥综合症
Sjogren's it is.
用静脉注射免疫抑制剂进行治疗
IV immunosuppressants to treat.
有要补充的吗
Anything?
这会使你的免疫系统恢复正常
This will calm your immune system.
这周内你就可以出院了
Should be out of here within the week.
我妈妈听到了一定很高兴
My mom will be happy to hear that.
我得到个实习机会  三周后开始
I've got an internship that starts in three weeks.
我想应该不是在马戏团吧
I take it it's not at a place with a big top.
是在我继父的律师事务所
It's at my stepdad's law office.
我知道我还不擅长扮演小丑
I know I'm not any good at being a clown yet,
但当我听到他们的笑声
but when I do get a laugh
看到孩子们眼里闪着喜悦  我很开心
and see those kids' eyes light up,
我还是孩子时  爸爸给我的就是这种感觉
that's how my Dad made me feel when I was a kid.
你得坚持这一点
You need to hang on to that.
我妈妈说他是个很有爱心的父亲
My mom says he was a loving father
但一直很穷  到处进行表演
but always broke and always on the road.
这样维持生计太傻了
It's just a stupid way to make a living.
你才十六岁  有大把的时间可以去赚钱
You're 16. Plenty of time to make money.
想和你的父亲建立心灵的联系
Wanting to build a connection with your dad
将他带给你的快乐传递下去
and pass on some of the joy that he gave you,
这想法一点都不傻
that's not stupid at all.
我来吧
I got it.
这  这是药物治疗导致的吗
Is, uh, is this because of the medication?
这正常吗
Is it normal?
不正常  不是干燥综合症
It's not normal, and it's not Sjogren's.
短暂性脑缺血发作  心包膜增厚
T.I.A., thickened pericardium,
现在他的鼻子和嘴巴都在流血
and now he's bleeding from his nose and mouth.
你抱着她干什么
What are you doing with her?
她
"Her"?
话说这个小开心果有名字吧
Surely this bundle of fun has an actual name.
这是苏菲
It's Sophie.
你的两个孩子都叫
Both your kids are named--
她是苏菲  另外一个是苏菲娅
She's Sophie. The other one's Sophia.
差别很大的
It's different enough.
它们确实有两个截然不同的衍生词
They actually have two completely different derivations.
实际上没有
No, they don't.
我现在没有心情争论
I wasn't in a strong negotiating position.
她怎么在这里
Why is she here?
露比带她来的
Ruby dropped her off.
她看起来有些担心
Seemed pretty upset.
显然有人忘记了今晚轮到爸爸带孩子
Apparently someone forgot that it was Daddy's night.
直到我说我会让你早点下班
She wasn't even gonna leave her
她才肯把孩子放这里
until I said that I was letting you off early.
妈的  我才回到团队
Damn it. I just started back on the team.
我的日程安排一团乱
My schedule's a mess.
如果你的孩子们也是原因之一
If your own kids are a scheduling item,
你或许该让其中之一离开
maybe you should let one of them move.
病人血小板数量很低
Patient has low platelets.
我觉得可能是弥散性血管内凝血
makes me think D.I.C.
看来她不赞成啊
She doesn't seem to like that idea.
你说的对哦
You're right.
他的血液涂片中没有裂红细胞
He has no schistocytes in his smear.
他的红细胞数也很低
He also has a low red count.
会不会是腹膜后出血
What if it's a retroperitoneal bleed?
胁腹部并没出现血斑
No Grey-Turner's sign.
她没有我抱她的时候开心哦
She wasn't fussing like that when I was holding her.
可能她喜欢我的声音
Maybe she likes the sound of my voice,
好奇怪啊  我和她没有血缘关系啊
which is weird because I have no genetic connection to her.
难道她分不清谁是亲生父亲
Could it be she doesn't know the difference?
你果然是孩子太多了
So many children of your own.
难怪对我和我宝宝的关系
No wonder you have such insight
有如此深刻的见解
into my relationship with my babies.
有道理
Good point.
我怎么能理解你呢
How could I comprehend that
可悲的给她们起一样的名字
you're too despised to keep them from having the same name,
压力太大记不住自己的日程
too overwhelmed to remember your own calendar,
都到这个地步了  还死要面子不承认
and too vain to admit that at this stage,
你对两个孩子来说都无关紧要
you don't matter to either baby.
白细胞数量低意味着感染
Low white count suggests infection.
如果你们都说对了呢
What if you're all right?
血小板低加上红细胞低加上白细胞低等于
Low platelets plus low red count plus low white count equals--
再生障碍性贫血
Aplastic anemia.
这孩子需要骨髓移植
Kid needs a bone marrow transplant.
除了亚当斯外  其他人
Everyone except Adams,
给他输入血小板  直到找到匹配的骨髓
transfuse his platelets till you find a match.
你上大学比别人晚了一个学期
You started college a semester late
因为你高中毕业晚了一个学期
because you left high school a semester late
因为高三时  你有五门不合格
because you had five incompletes in your junior year.
你想以我一个学期的不佳表现
And you're offering one bad semester
来证明我父母毁了我吗
as proof that my parents screwed me up?
在那之前学习马马虎虎  之后一直是优
Did OK before that. Straight As after that.
我那时处于叛逆期
I went through a rebellious phase.
不说我都知道
Don't tell me.
妈妈和爸爸吵得面红耳赤
Mom and Dad were at each other's throats
你以一塌糊涂的成绩来引起关注
and the academic crisis was a cry for help.
抱歉毁了你的世界观
Sorry to mess with your world view,
但我活得很好
but I'm not messed up.
我父母没有毁了我
So my parents couldn't have messed me up.
母亲的白细胞抗原只有3/6匹配
Mom's HLA is only a 3/6 match.
祖母的匹配情况更糟糕
Maternal grandmother's worse than that.
你把孩子安置在哪里了
Where did you unload the baby?
产科病房  闭嘴
Maternity ward. Shut up.
你应该意识到你正在印证豪斯的观点
You realize you're making House's argument for him.
你是指请日托照顾孩子的家长
The part where he said any parent who uses day care
该将孩子送到大陆另一边吗
should ship their child across the country?
不  是他说孩子不需要你的那部分
No, the part where he said that baby doesn't need you.
你每周只有一两天有权带孩子
You've only got her a couple days a week
而此期间绝大多时间孩子都和护士在一起
and most of that's spent with a rotating cast of nurses.
所以她老爸也喜欢围着护士转
That's how Daddy likes to spend his time too.
闭嘴
Shut up.
直系堂兄也不匹配
First cousin's also a whiff.
亲属的测试结果都没戏
So much for genetics mattering.
我试试看骨髓登记库
I'll try the marrow registry.
朴克医生正在查找骨髓库
Dr. Park is searching the registry.
在等待期间给他注射血小板
Transfusing his platelets
会帮他保持健康
will keep him healthy while we wait.
你确定父亲那边没有人了吗
Are you sure there's no one on the father's side of the family?
如果有人匹配的话  事情就会顺利很多
If one of them's a match, that'd speed things up a lot.
他父母早逝
His parents died young.
他是独子
He was an only child.
就我所知没有亲人在世
There's no living relatives that I know of.
很快会有对策的
Something will turn up soon.
很快是多快  他会落掉很多课程吗
How soon is soon? Will he miss a lot of school?
实际上我在想拿到高中毕业证就好了
I'm actually thinking of just getting my GED.
那你凭什么上所好的大学呢
How do you expect to get into a good college?
我会学习魔术和变戏法
I'm gonna take classes on magic and juggling
试着有所发展
and try to make a go of this.
本  只要你成绩好
Ben, you keep your grades up,
想干什么工作都可以
you can do anything in the world.
比如说  当无聊的办公室白领吗
Like what? Work in some boring office?
你认为我生父
I mean, do you think my father
会在这种工作上浪费时间吗
would have done that for ten minutes?
你不记得你父亲  你不知道
You don't remember your father. You don't know...
我想和他建立心灵上的联系
I want to build a connection with him,
将他给我带来的快乐传递下去
pass on some of the...the joy that he gave me.
我的背  好痛
My, uh, my back hurts.
他的血压在下降
His BP is dropping.
我们认为负债问题应该都解决了
We think we've dealt with all the liability issues.
我在开会
I'm in a meeting.
对不起
Sorry.
因为你呼叫了我  我不想让你久等
Since you paged me, I didn't want to keep you waiting.
我是呼叫了你  接下来就和你谈
Yeah, I paged you, which means you're next.
没问题  我等着
That's cool. I'll wait.
是个不错的开始
That's a good start.
我们逐条分析
Let's go through it point by point.
首先
First up...
我再打给你们
I'll call you back.
这是刚收到的
Just got this.
美国风湿病协会
The American Associate of Rheumatology
想让你周六九点在大西洋城做个演讲
wants you to speak, 9:00, Saturday, in Atlantic City.
纽辛格医生最后时刻放了他们鸽子
Dr. Neusinger canceled on them at the last minute.
我讨厌开会
I hate conferences.
这次会议很隆重  而且又是黄金档的演讲
This is a big one, and it's the premium slot.
我想让你去
I'd like you to do it.
我会和你的假释官说明的
I'll clear it with your parole officer.
我要怎么回报你呢
What do I need to do for you?
把我加倍的门诊时间减回去
Halve the clinic hours that you recently doubled
把我减半的预算加回来
and double the hooker budget that you recently halved.
正如你所言  都是些小钱罢了
I think you refer to it as petty cash.
好的
Fine.
只是有一点
Just one thing.
我会让他们把你的演讲安排在上午
I'm gonna ask them to put you on in the morning.
算是助人为乐吧
We're doing them a favor.
你何必在那里过夜呢
Why should you have to spend the night?
你说黄金档应该是晚上九点吧
You said that 9:00 was the premium slot.
我的意思是  我干活总得干到位吧
I mean, I want to feel like I've earned my hookers.
到时候那地方会很混乱的
The place'll be a madhouse,
特别是因为
especially since it's two miles
那里离同时进行的卢比奥拳击赛只有两英里
from the Rubio Fight at the exact same time.
计划不错
Nice try.
你冒充纽辛格打电话去取消演讲
You called up, pretended to be Neusinger, cancelled,
然后又推荐你自己当候补
and suggested yourself as a replacement.
你去看比赛  就得进监狱
You go to that fight, you go to prison.
进监狱真是多此一举
But that'd be redundant,
在这里就有个愤怒的黑人
when I have an angry black guy
伺机想要爆我菊花
waiting for me to drop the soap right here.
你还是快去做那些加倍的门诊吧
Better go do some of those clinic hours I recently doubled.
给我做尿检
Test my urine.
看来我的诊断有误
Looks like I was wrong about my diagnosis.
是的  我得了糖尿病
Yeah. I have diabetes.
不是糖尿病  但你也没得忧郁症
No, but you're not a hypochondriac.
否则在我否定糖尿病之后
Or you would have imagined some new disease
你又会想象出新的疾病
after I shot down the first one.
这是谁的尿样
So whose urine is that?
是你得糖尿病但没医疗保险的女朋友的
Diabetic girlfriend without health insurance?
我没骗你  我是病了
It's not a scam. I'm sick.
我现在脚踝都肿了
Now I have swollen ankles.
医学上这叫脚踝赘肉
The medical term is cankles.
是不是有哪个我不知道的
Is there some black market in insulin
贩卖胰岛素的黑市
that I don't know about?
我这病是遗传的
It's in my genes.
我老爸五十岁时得了糖尿病
My old man got diabetes at 50.
我老哥也是在五十岁时发病的
My older brother got it at 50.
我刚好满五十
I just turned 50.
别把糖尿病说得像块传家宝似的
Well, it's a great argument if diabetes was a gold watch.
和我父亲一样  我也有坐骨神经痛
I got sciatica, like my dad.
还有IV度痔疮
Class-four hemorrhoids, like him.
我得未雨绸缪
I need to get a jump on this thing.
我们不得不中止输血
We had to stop the transfusion.
病人对捐献者的血小板过敏
Patient's having an allergic reaction to donor platelets.
母亲这边的亲属配型都不符
No one in mom's family's a match,
据她所知  父亲那边没有健在的亲属
and as far as she knows, Dad has no living relatives.
他死了好几年了
It's been years since he died.
如果孩子他爸死于黑色素瘤
If the kid's Dad died young of melanoma,
像她这样一个保护欲过强的母亲
how come the overprotective mom
怎么会不带儿子去看皮肤科呢
never took him to a dermatologist?
你还给不给我做尿检了
Are you gonna test my urine or what?
不是糖尿病
Not diabetes.
对血小板进行交叉配血
Use cross-matched platelets.
找些与他自身相近的血液给他输
Try to find the patient some blood that's closer to his own.
还要问清楚小丑一世的真实死因
And get the real story on clown, senior's death.
孩子他妈有所隐藏
Mom's hiding something.
很可能是和病因有关的信息
It's a good bet that it's medically relevant.
苹果汁
Apple juice.
简简单单升血糖
Easiest way to fake a spike in blood sugar.
患黑色素瘤的家族史
His family history of melanoma
可能会改变他的细胞形态
may have affected his cellular outlook.
除非我们能获知
If we had more data on
他父亲患的是哪种黑色素瘤
the exact type of melanoma his father had.
否则  我们很难找到相符的骨髓配型
Otherwise, we might not be able to find a marrow match.
他没有得黑色素瘤
He never had melanoma.
那他怎么死的
How did he die?
他没死
He didn't.
他住在彭索金  换了个名字
He lives in Pennsauken under a different name,
现在叫米歇尔·戈登
Mitchell Gordon.
这事你怎么能瞒着我  瞒着本
How could you keep this from me? From Ben?
难道真的要让他知道
He really needs to know
他父亲只是他人生中一个过客
his Dad just breezed in and out of his life,
一直烂醉如泥而不负责任
drunk and incoherent?
我宁可让他对父亲抱有美好的回忆
It's better to think the man's dead but decent.
你知道我得邀请别人去看卢比奥拳击赛
You realize I have to invite someone else to the Rubio Fight?
不行  我才不管呢
Nope. No realization whatsoever.
你脚上还绑着个追踪器呢
You have a Lojack on your leg.
在付费电视上看比赛我很满足了
I was happy watching the fight on pay-per-view.
是你坚持要去大西洋城的
You're the one who insisted we go to Atlantic City.
你的生父是个规规矩矩的牧师
Your biological father was a decent, god-fearing minister.
你的养父是个铁石心肠的混蛋
The guy who raised you was a cold-hearted jerk.
我在揣测你为什么吃准了
I'm trying to figure out why you're so convinced
亚当斯肯定受过父母的伤害
Adams has parentally inflicted damage.
你在转移话题
You're trying to deflect.
转移话题的是你
Now you are.
你强迫自己认为父母都会毁了他们的孩子
You have to believe that every parent screws up every child.
不然你就要承认你自己毁了美好的童年
Or you were screwed out of a decent childhood.
我规规矩矩的牧师老爸
My decent Daddy of the cloth
找我的已婚老妈干些见不得人的勾当
was also being indecent with my married Mom.
他很可能还有别的孩子要带去游乐场
He probably would have taken other kids to the playground.
不是我的错  我家教不好
It's not my fault. Bad parenting.
米歇尔·戈登
Mitchell Gordon?
我已经信教了  你们走吧
I've already got a religion. Go away.
我们是医生
We're doctors.
你儿子本住院了  普林斯顿普雷斯波罗教学医院
Your son Ben is in the hospital, at Princeton-Plainsboro.
他病得很重
He's very sick.
我没有儿子  现在没有了
Yeah, well, I don't have a son. Not anymore.
我们知道其中有些过结
We know there are some issues there,
但你的骨髓很可能能救他
but your bone marrow could cure him.
离这两英里有家医院
There's a hospital two miles from here.
只需做个简单的检查
It's a simple test.
你说他在普林斯顿普雷斯波罗教学医院
You said he was at Princeton-Plainsboro?
他母亲认为在不同的医院
His mother feels it's better
做检查比较好
to do the test at a different hospital.
我就当没这个儿子吧
Well, I guess I don't have a son anymore.
豪斯是不会放弃的
House isn't gonna give up.
你就和他说说你父母吧  要么说个谎
Just tell him about your parents or make up a lie.
我不想说谎
I don't want to lie.
我不想证实他那个可笑的理论
I don't want to validate his ridiculous theory.
一点不可笑啊
It's not ridiculous.
即使完全出于善意  父母还是会伤害到子女
Even the best-intentioned parents end up damaging their kids.
你是个聪明成功的医生
You're a smart, successful doctor.
你哪里受到伤害了啊
How much damage could you have?
你知道我怎么会对医学感兴趣的吗
Know how I got interested in medicine?
我母亲喝醉的时候  没法照顾我
When my mother drank, she couldn't handle me,
就把我锁在父亲的书房里
so she locked me in my father's study.
我哭喊着  撞门  但无济于事
Only so many hours you can cry and bang on the door
几个小时后  我放弃了  找了些书来读
before you give up, find something to read.
我们的家庭在某方面都有缺陷
We all have family dysfunction.
这就是我们成功的原因
That's why we're successful.
为了弥补那个缺陷
To fill that hole.
我父母有很多钱
My parents have a lot of money,
但不是合法赚来的
but they didn't make it legally.
白领犯罪吗
White-collar crime?
是从纸牌游戏开始的
It started with card games.
高赌注的扑克
High-stakes poker.
后来我爸爸开始接触麻醉毒品
Then my dad got into narcotics,
起初只是卖  后来自己也开始用
at first just selling but then using too,
不然他也绝不会卷入贩卖奴隶的买卖
or he never would have gotten into the slave trade.
大部分是孩子  很容易塞进小箱子里
Children mostly. Easier to pack in small crates.
而且运费要便宜得多
Plus the shipping's a lot cheaper.
连同事你都不信任
Won't even trust a co-worker.
你父母到底对你做了什么
What did your parents do to you?
你得亲自去见他了
You have to go see him yourself.
他都不愿意开第二次门
He wouldn't even come to the door a second time.
好吧  我开车去一趟
Okay. I'll drive over there.
是胸腔积液
It's a pleural effusion.
他之前有过出血问题
He had a bleeding problem earlier.
一定是血液流进了肺
Must be bleeding into his lungs.
但是没有血
Except there's no blood.
这说明了什么
What does that mean?
说明你不用去了
It means you don't have to make that drive.
不是骨髓的问题
The problem isn't his marrow.
是肝脏
It's his liver.
肝功能衰竭  解释了所有症状
Liver failure. Explains everything.
问题是  什么才能解释肝功能衰竭
The question is, what explains the liver failure?
不是感染
It's not an infection.
我们用了抗生素  但是他没有反应
We tried antibiotics, but he's not responding.
我很好奇  他妈妈为什么要
More curiously, what explains the mom
撒谎说他爸已经入土了
lying about dad pushing up squirting daisies?
这就是你打算去看拳击游戏的计划吗
This is how you plan to get to the boxing game?
你没什么看她
Why are you looking at her?
因为我震惊了  我总得看点什么
'Cause I'm stunned, and I have to look at something.
比赛  回合赛  争霸赛  竞赛  大赛  海伦娜
Match, bout, fight, contest, day, Helena.
几乎所有的词都能放在"拳击"后面
Almost anything works after "Boxing,"
除了"游戏"
except the word "Game."
你更大的问题在于
Your bigger problem is,
设计那玩意的人不是傻子
people who design those things aren't idiots.
你能相信她以前是在监狱工作的吗
Can you believe she used to work in the can?
没有东西是无坚不摧的
Nothing is tamper-proof.
是蛋白质合成的问题
It's a synthetic problem.
他的肝脏无法合成蛋白质
His liver's not synthesizing proteins,
导致体液渗漏出了血管
so fluid is leaking out of his blood vessels.
还有  他妈妈就是个自私的混蛋
And mom's a selfish jerk.
她另攀高枝  嫁了律师
She traded up, married a lawyer,
想忘掉那个低贱的马戏团小丑
wants to forget the lowly circus clown.
你为父亲辩护是因为你觉得自己就是个混蛋
You're defending the father because you feel like a jerk
因为你在两个烤箱里烤面包
for baking buns in two different ovens.
你想要相信那虚无缥缈的生理联系
You want to believe the mythical biological connection
为你出轨找借口
excuses being a man slut.
不知怎的我开始质疑你的专业水准了
I don't know why I'm starting to doubt your expertise.
你的确登了个分类广告
You do have a classified ad
现在手里还有一根铁棒子
and a piece of metal.
它是温控的  不能靠蛮力
It's temperature that sets it off, not force.
铆钉一撬开  我就把加热板塞进去
The rivets go pop, I slide in the heating pad.
毛毛雨啦
Easy peasy.
病人更像是有高氨血症的问题
More likely the patient has a hyperammonemic problem.
他的肝脏无法清理血液中的毒素
His liver's not cleaning out his blood.
累积的毒素导致了所有的问题
The buildup of toxins is causing everything.
我维护爸爸是因为他很惨
I'm defending the dad because he got screwed.
他失去儿子之后又失去了工作
After he lost his son, he lost his job.
反复出入戒毒所  放弃做小丑
Been in and out of rehab, gave up clowning.
没错  作为一个父亲  我同情他
Yes, as a parent, I empathize.
要我说我们该告诉那孩子
I say we tell the kid.
他未成年  他妈妈是他的监护人
He's a minor, the mom's his guardian,
而且这跟医学也没关系
and it's not even medically relevant.
她剥夺了十二年父子相处的时间
She robbed them of 12 years together.
或者她应该早点踹了他爸
Or she ripped off the band-aid too late.
她让她儿子确定自己是小丑的后代
That memory that she let son of bozo establish
导致他本可以在波兰过高品质的生活
is making him chase his father's moronic profession
结果却在追求一份他爸干的白痴工作
when he could be living the high life in Portland.
当然说波兰只是打个比方
And I mean that metaphorically, of course.
你是想给我秀下你酷炫牛X的应急手法吧
This is where you dazzle me with your contingency plan.
我明白为啥人们都不愿
I see why employers are reluctant
雇用以前是诈骗犯的人了
to hire ex-cons.
病人怎么办
Well, what about the patient?
到底是高氨血症还是蛋白合成不足
Is the problem hyperammonemic or synthetic?
不能两个都治
Can't treat for both.
一个需要血液透析  一个需要肝脏移植
One requires hemodialysis, the other a liver transplant,
我们都找不到和那孩子匹配的骨髓
and we couldn't even get the kid a marrow match.
征得他妈妈的同意给他灌满蛋白质
Get the mom's consent to pump him full of protein.
如果是蛋白质合成不足
If it's a synthetic problem,
液体会渗入他的胸腔  导致心力衰竭
more fluid will leak into his chest and his heart will fail.
如果是高氨血症
If it's hyperammonemic,
毒素会淹没他的身体  他会陷入昏迷
toxins will overwhelm his body and he'll go into a coma.
你是不是只喜欢有致死性风险的检查
Do you only like tests that involve the risk of death?
确实有又慢又没用的检查
There are some slower, less conclusive tests,
不过干嘛要冒那个风险呢
but why take that risk?
在这里
In here.
我的天  是水
Oh, my God. The water.
这完全是我的错
This is completely my fault.
这有很大的风险
There are very serious risks,
但如果我们不搞清楚他得的是什么病
but if we don't figure out what he has,
我们就无从下手治疗
we can't treat him at all.
我这么说也许有点过份
I may be a little out of bounds here,
但以防万一有什么并发症
but in case there are complications,
这也许是向你儿子坦白的好时机
it might be a good time to come clean to your son,
让他父亲来探望
let his father visit.
这是有"点"过份吗
A little out of bounds?
我不知道发生过什么  但人人都会犯错
I don't know the history, but everyone makes mistakes.
你儿子很崇拜他
Your son worships him.
医生说得对
Doctor's right about that.
是吗  他是什么时候开始崇拜的
Oh, yeah? And when did he learn that?
他鼓励本辍学的时候吗
When he encouraged Ben to drop out of school?
米歇尔不是本的父亲
Mitchell is not Ben's father
他只不过是个精子捐献者
any more than a sperm donor would have been.
豪斯医生
Dr. House?
除非你是个锁匠
Unless you're a locksmith
或者跟政府合作的电工  否则我很忙
or an electrician with political contacts, I'm busy.
我丈夫看过你的门诊
My husband saw you in the clinic.
想要治疗糖尿病
Wants treatment for diabetes.
对你们即将到来的离婚致哀
My condolences on your forthcoming divorce.
他不停的想象症状
He keeps imagining symptoms,
现在我不得不给他做那些恶心的降糖餐
and now I have to make him these awful anti-diabetic meals.
既然我没打算给他做检查
Since I have no intention of testing him,
也没打算治疗他  或者给他做饭
treating him, or cooking for him--
你可以给我开个假的胰岛素处方吗
Could you write me a fake prescription for insulin?
假处方的好处就在于
The advantage of fake prescriptions is,
不用非得让真的医生开
you don't have to be a real doctor to write one.
告诉我注射什么在他大腿里是安全的就好
Just tell me what's safe to inject in his thigh.
他的症状就会消失
His symptoms will go away
然后我就可以告诉他他从来没得过糖尿病
and then I can show him he was never sick.
水行吗
Water?
想象的药不是我的专长
Imaginary medicine is not my specialty.
我确实有个想象的同事
I do have an imaginary colleague
刚刚想象的传呼了我一下
who's just sent me an imaginary page.
想象我有多抱歉
Imagine how sorry I am.
还在为刚才实验室的事生气吗
Still mad about what happened in the lab?
我没生气  我这是专业
I'm not mad. I'm being professional.
你说你挺好
You claim you're not screwed up.
你也许真的相信了
You may even believe it.
但是豪斯不信  我也不信
But House doesn't and I don't,
所以你可以等到
so you can wait
他在你爸妈的草坪上扎营
till he camps out on your parents' lawn
或者你可以承认你跟我们是一撮的
or you can admit you don't live on some higher plane
然后再谢我
and thank me later.
我的  我的眼睛感觉很奇怪
My, uh, my eye feels weird.
我怎么了
What's happening to me?
你看起来很疲倦
You look tired.
我讨厌人们这么说
I hate it when people say that.
我知道  我看起来很糟
I know, I look bad.
我以为你昨晚会早睡的
I thought you were gonna go to bed early last night.
我白痴一般的跟我闺蜜们出去
Like an idiot, I went out with my girlfriends
假装我还有生活
to pretend I have a life,
当我只是在跟一群对"妈妈"没兴趣的
when all I did was flirt with guys
男生调情的时候
who'd have no interest in a mom,
想念我迫不及待想要摆脱的宝宝
miss the baby I couldn't wait to get rid of,
然后又被我妈大吼一通
and then get yelled at by my mom
就因为在外面待到太晚
for staying out too late.
-你得有自己住的地方  -没错
- You need your own place. - Yes.
我搬回家是因为我住的地方四季漏风
I moved back home because it was too drafty at the four seasons.
那就回医院工作呗
So go back to work at the hospital.
日托的开销比我当护士赚的多多了
Day care costs more than what I earned as a nurse.
你没考虑过差一点的吗
Have you considered sub-standard day care?
要不你今晚就住在这
Why don't you stay here tonight?
我的意思是你可以睡客房
No. I mean, in the guest room.
我能继续照看孩子
I'll watch the baby again,
你也能睡个好觉
and you can get a real night's sleep.
你愿意这么做吗
You'd do that?
双赢嘛
Win-win.
妈妈睡个好觉
Mommy gets a rest,
爸爸跟他的小天使多处会
daddy gets more time with his little angel.
后面的衣橱里有毛巾
There's some sweats in the closet in the back.
幸运的小孩
Lucky girl.
又能和爸爸睡一起了
Gets another sleepover with da-da.
还是不一样的
It makes a difference.
不是吗
Doesn't it?
你昨晚没回传呼
Didn't answer your page last night.
不好意思  电池没电了
Sorry. Battery died.
我们给病人注射了类固醇
We got the patient's eye back in place
他的眼球复位了
with steroid injections,
不过眼球肿胀表明不是肝脏的问题
But a bulging eyeball means it's not a liver problem.
他母亲在孩子的病越来越糟时
And mom's determination to keep dad away,
仍决定不让父亲插手此事
even as her kid gets sicker and sicker,
意味着她有更大的隐情
means she's got more to hide.
这与诊断无关
It's not diagnostically relevant.
我们就别管了
Let's let it drop.
你刚失去了我的支持
You just lost my vote.
你可是父母权益的疯狂拥护者
You flip-flopped on parental rights.
我已经尽力说服他母亲了
I've been trying to persuade the mother,
但那是她儿子  她做主
but it's her son, so it's her call.
你的想法变化很大
Well, that's very evolved of you.
这么巨大的思想转变可不常见
Don't usually see darwinian changes over breakfast.
你跟菲尔好好谈了下
You made nice-nice with Phil, you decided that
你觉得他能成为一名称职的父亲
he'd make a decent father for thing 2 after all.
我昨晚和苏菲在一起
I had Sophie again last night
露比睡在我家客房
and Ruby slept in my guest room,
这跟菲尔没半点关系
which has nothing to do with Phil,
他永远不会是我孩子的父亲
who will never be a father to my children.
血管神经性水肿有可能造成迅速肿胀
Angioneurotic edema can cause rapid swelling.
我们在这聊正事呢
Hey, we're having a conversation here.
没有腹痛
No abdominal pain.
和露比与孩子在同一屋檐下
So that must have been nice, having Ruby
感觉一定很美好
and the baby under one roof.
没错  女儿在我家我感觉很好
Yes, it was nice having my daughter in my home.
这也是我希望她姐姐住在我家附近的原因
That's why I would like her sister to live near my home.
全身性水肿
Anasarca?
那样肿胀会随重力移动
Swelling would have followed gravity.
这样整个关于父母的讨论不是又回到原点了
Isn't that getting this whole parenting thing ass backwards?
你不是该搞明白为使孩子们过的更好
Aren't you supposed to figure out what you can sacrifice
你需要付出的代价是什么吗
to maximize their niceness?
你觉得我的代价就该是从他们的生活中消失吗
And do you think I should sacrifice myself from their lives?
只是其中一个而已
Just one life,
直到另一个的母亲找到比你更好的人
until the other one's mommy meets someone nicer than you.
进展如此迅速的局部肿胀
Swelling that fast and localized
一般来源于淋巴结
has to come from the lymph nodes.
博吉特淋巴瘤
Burkitt's lymphoma.
肿胀
Swelling.
脚踝赘肉
Cankles.
那不是博吉特淋巴瘤的症状
That's not a symptom of Burkitt's.
-你是想说是... -就是博吉特淋巴瘤
- Are you saying it's-- - It's Burkitt's.
准备化疗
Prep him for chemo.
我认为你应该允许豪斯去
I think you should give House permission
亚特兰大城
to go to Atlantic city.
我们会去风湿病学会议的
We'll stop by the rheumatology conference.
-各得其所  -不
- Everyone's covered. - No.
那家伙赢得了去看场拳击赛的权利
The guy has earned the right to go to one boxing match.
他应要完成了每件事
He's done everything you've asked--
组建了自己的科室
Funded and staffed his own department.
甚至连交通规则都没违反
Hasn't even broken as much as a traffic law.
你说的没错
You're right.
那你会让他去
So you'll let him go?
不
No.
我明白他为什么想去看那场比赛
I get why he wants to go to that fight.
我自己也想去
I'd love to go myself,
这也是我阻止他的原因
which is kind of why I have to stop him.
我的职责就是做个混蛋
My job is to be the jerk.
必须让豪斯相信我的权威在他之上
House has to believe that I have authority over him.
他就是没法任人指挥
He can't function under someone's thumb.
我明白  这意味着你也不能去
I know, which means you can't go either.
你的职责是做他的朋友
Your job is to be his friend,
呆在这陪着他
to stay here and sit with him
在电视前看那场比赛然后一起说我的坏话
and watch the fight on pay-per-view while bitching about me.
如果我们都尽职尽责
If we both do our jobs,
我们可能真能让他安全度过假释期
we might actually get him through his parole.
你是对的
You're right.
不好意思我们在这出现
Sorry to show up like this.
我还等着一群律师呢
I was expecting a battery of lawyers.
没有律师
No lawyers.
菲尔有些话想跟你说
Phil had something that he would like to say,
我觉得他应该当面跟你说
so I thought that he should say it in person.
直接跟你说要把瑞秋
It was wrong of me to confront you
带去波特兰是我的不对
about taking Rachel to Portland.
你不想搬去波特兰吗
You don't want to move to Portland?
我当然想  不过这也关系到你女儿
Of course I do, but this is about your daughter too
没有你的支持我是不会做这样的事的
and I'm not gonna do something like this without your support.
你们俩是想通过扮红脸和红脸
So you guys are trying to manipulate me
来操纵我的想法吗
by playing good cop/good cop?
你就把我想得这么不堪吗
Is that how little you think of me?
很明显你又开始给豪斯卖命了
It's clear you're back working for house.
周末你来接苏菲时再见吧
I will see you this weekend when you pick up Sophie.
苏菲娅
Sophia.
我们已经开始叫她苏菲了
We actually started calling her Sophie.
没错
Yeah.
很好
Great.
挺可爱的
It's cute.
脚踝
Cankles.
你给我的处方有什么问题吗
Is there some problem with the prescription you gave me?
我很虚弱  我体重又涨了
I'm faint. I've been gaining more weight.
我觉得我需要更大剂量
I think I need a bigger dose.
如果你把他的安慰剂剂量加倍他会淹死的
If you double his placebo, he might drown.
还有  你没告诉我你心率缓慢
Also, you forgot to mention that your heart rate is slow.
我的心率并不
My--my heart rate is not--
-52  -医学术语就叫作缓慢
- 52. - The technical term is slow.
你吃的那些可怕的抗糖尿病餐
Those awful anti-diabetic meals you eat,
是不是有小白菜
do they contain bok choy?
有一磅左右 每天都有
A pound of it. Every day.
小白菜含有硫代葡萄糖酸盐会抑制甲状腺功能
Bok choy has glucosinolates which inhibit thyroid function
从而引起你所有的症状
and account for all your symptoms.
那么说不是糖尿病
So this isn't diabetes?
真是个悲剧的讽刺
You have a bad case of irony.
你吃用来阻止你生病的食物
The food that you're eating to stop making you sick
反而让你得病了
is making you sick.
也许我根本就没遗传我爸的基因
Hey, maybe I don't have my father's crummy genes after all.
另一方面  没有你爸  你的肥胖
On the other hand, maybe you're fat enough
可能也足以使你患糖尿病
to get diabetes even without him.
真不敢相信我得了癌症
I can't believe I have cancer.
我们发现的早  应该没事的
We caught it early. You should be okay.
我可能会死  我还没去过什么地方干过什么呢
I could die. I never went anywhere, did anything.
如果我父亲还活着
If my father had lived,
一切都会不一样的
everything would have been different.
你母亲和继父都很爱你
Your mom and stepdad love you.
他们给了你一个很棒的家
They've given you a great home.
这很重要
That counts for a lot.
他不行了  各器官都在衰竭
He's crashing. Everything's shutting down.
肾衰竭  肺衰竭  心脏衰竭
Renal failure, lung failure, heart failure,
都发生在我们进行化疗之前
all before we started chemo.
博吉特淋巴瘤发展速度很快  但不会这么快
Burkitt's lymphoma is fast-moving, but not this fast.
别急  重症监护病房在拉丁语中等于慢慢来
No rush. ICU stands for take your time in latin.
多重动脉瘤
Multiple aneurysms.
那意味着短暂性脑缺血发作后的一切症状
That would mean that every symptom after his T.I.A.
不过是巧合
Was a coincidence.
胆固醇栓子
Cholesterol Emboli?
答对了  完全吻合  去查病历
Bingo. Fits perfectly. Check the file.
证实我们给他做了大型腹腔手术
Confirm that we did major abdominal surgery on him
却又完全遗忘了
and then completely forgot about it.
豪斯
House.
你来这里做什么
What the hell are you doing here?
我被告知这可能是见儿子的最后机会
I was told that this might be my last chance to see my son.
你没有这个权力  这与你无关
You had no right! This is none of your business!
-不是我  -是我叫他来的
- I didn't. - I called him.
他是本心目中的英雄
This man's Ben's hero.
就让他们在一起待五分钟
Let them spend five minutes together.
不  都给我出去
No! Get out of here!
等等
Wait.
你性侵犯了自己的儿子
You sexually molested your son.
你走路的姿势
Your walk.
脊髓痨
Tabes dorsalis.
你的梅毒已经到了晚期
You have late-stage syphilis,
你在大约十二年前将梅毒传给我们的病人
which you gave to our patient presumably 12 years ago,
因此母亲才极力反对父子团圆
which also explains why mom is not big on family reunions.
我不该来的
I shouldn't be here.
我们测验过梅毒  为阴性
We tested him for syphilis. He was negative.
十二年过后
After 12 years,
他体内的活性病菌已经销声匿迹
the active infection would have died down
只有部分存在于脑动脉
everywhere except the arteries in his brain,
顺便躲过了我们的测验
where it could hide out from our tests.
六岁小李刚
But when that six-year-old heckler
一拳打在他蛋蛋上
punched him in his juggling pins,
激起了他骨盆中处于休眠状态的病菌
it kicked up the dormant bacteria in his pelvis.
我们给他用的免疫抑制剂让病菌得以肆虐
The immunosuppressants we gave him sent it into overdrive.
我们给他用的抗体
The antibiotics we gave him
其实已经开始消灭梅毒
actually started destroying the syphilis.
但它们如同火上泼水
But like pouring water on a fire,
激起一片有毒烟气尘埃
that led to a trail of toxic smoke and ash
使得他的免疫系统过度补偿
which made his immune system overcompensate.
贝佐尔德-亚里施反射
Severe Jarisch-Herxheimer reaction.
这是真的吗
Is this true?
没错  真有贝佐尔德-亚里施反射这回事
Yes, Jarisch-Herxheimer is real.
听起来有点儿傻  不过...
It sounds silly, but...
哦  你说的是那个...  好吧
Oh, you mean the--the--right.
我在他的衣服上发现了痕迹
I found stains on his clothes.
他当时还不懂  也没有受到创伤的迹象
He didn't understand and he didn't seem traumatized.
我试图跟他说起这件事  可是不久之后他就不记得了
I kept trying to talk to him, but before long, he'd forgotten,
而且他看起来
And he seemed--
看起来很快乐  一切正常
And he seemed happy and he seemed normal.
所以你把父亲撵走
So you made daddy go away
编好理由让孩子永远不会去找他
and you made sure junior had no reason to go looking.
我只是为了保护他
I was just trying to protect him,
像我一开始就应该做的那样
like I should have done from the start.
对不起
Sorry.
静脉注射盘尼西林和抗坏死抗体
IV penicillin and anti-tnf antibodies,
他会好起来的
He'll be fine.
被亲爹强奸这事除外
Apart from the whole daddy-rape thing.
这事还没完
We're not done.
是还没完
No, we are not.
通知病人父亲的性伴侣
Notify the dad's sexual partners.
通知他的雇主  房东
Notify his employer, his landlord.
还有警察
Notify the police.
我指那孩子
I meant the kid.
难道我们不告诉他  他被侵犯了
We're not gonna tell him he was molested?
让他痛不欲生还是让你丢掉行医执照
To make him miserable or to forfeit your license?
告诉他真相
To tell him the truth.
他还是处子  怎么会得性病
He's a virgin. How do we explain the STD?
这是医学诊断  让家长见鬼去
It's a medical diagnosis. Screw the parents.
孩子是我们的病人
The kid's our patient.
我猜等那孩子醒过来
I guess Taub's got a tough choice to make
陶博要有个艰难抉择了
when the kid wakes up.
为什么是我的抉择
Why is it my choice?
因为你当爸爸了
'cause you're a dad.
我们其他人怎么会懂
How could the rest of us possibly understand?
我得了什么病
What was-- what was wrong with me?
是梅毒
It's called syphilis.
没有性生活也能得这病吗
Uh, you--you can get that without having sex?
我没告诉他
I didn't tell him.
你的心在说他需要知道
Your heart said he needed to know.
你的头脑清楚他不知道最好
Your brain knew he's better off without it.
随心所欲很容易
Following your heart is easy.
听从头脑的抉择很难
Following your brain is tough.
尤其是在任由低级器官
Especially after years of following
支配了那么多年之后
that much smaller third organ.
所以说天下的孩子都会被父母毁掉
That's why all parents screw up all children.
晚上好
Evening.
欲擒故纵  假作毫不关心
Clever tactic, pretending you're not interested anymore.
这怎么会是欲擒故纵
How could that possibly work as a tactic?
事实是  我看到了你生命中不完整的地方
The fact is, once I saw those incompletes,
我知道你也被父母毁了
I knew your parents screwed you up.
细节不过是调味料而已
The details are just gravy.
你错了
You're wrong.
你有的证据只能证明其它事情的发生
The only evidence you have is proof of something else.
我离家出走过
I ran away from home.
因为你父母很差劲
Because you had lousy parents.
因为我的父母不差
Because I didn't.
我朋友们的父母不是离婚就是出轨
All my friends' parents were divorced or having affairs
要么就连自己孩子的生日都忘了
or barely knew their kids' birthdays.
你嫉妒他们的扭曲
You envied their dysfunction?
我当时以为  挫折给了他们深度
I-I thought it made them deeper somehow.
真是愚蠢
It was stupid.
我搭便车到曼哈顿
I hitchhiked to Manhattan,
和一个大我很多的男人同居
moved in with an older guy.
不到两个月  我就跑回家了
In two months, I came running home.
我父母几年后才从中恢复
It took my parents years to get over it.
自那之后你开始出类拔萃
That's when you started to excel.
你是为了补偿他们
You were making it up to them.
你的父母毁了你  原因就是他们没有毁你
Your parents screwed you up by not screwing you up.
我只是有一点点希望被毁
How does briefly wishing I was screwed up
也能算是毁了
make me screwed up?
被父母毁掉是普遍现象
It's normal to be screwed up.
连被毁都能浪漫化  才是毁得最严重的
It's really screwed up to romanticize it.
我猜这就是你要在囚犯中间工作的原因
I guess that's why you wanted to work with prisoners.
这是我要跟你工作的原因
It's why I wanted to work with you.
我的确是欲擒故纵
It was a tactic.
克里斯
Chris.
我得跟你和菲尔谈谈
I need to talk to you and Phil.
没出什么事吧
Is everything okay?
没有
Yeah.
我不能让你们搬走
I can't let you move.
你开车大老远过来
You drove all the way out here
就是为了重复你早就说的话
just to tell us what you already told us.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
豪斯
House, open up.
我不想错过开场
I don't want to miss the opening bell.
豪斯
House?